

R&D ENGINEER

■ tiagoprata@ymail.com | ☐ TiagoPrata | ☐ tiago-prata

Summary.

Current R&D Engineer at ABB. 7+ years experience combining industrial needs in programming skills and academic knowledge. Passionate for learning and teaching and fascinated by control theory. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Education

IFSP (Sao Paulo Federal Institute of Technology)

Sao Paulo, Brazil

M.S. IN AUTOMATION AND CONTROL ENGINEERING

Jan. 2018 - Apr. 2020 (present)

• System Identification and Model Predictive Control applied on MIMO systems

UNICAMP (University of Campinas)

Campinas, Brazil

DEEP LEARNING FOR IMAGE RECOGNITION

2017 (short course)

• Utilization of Keras library (python) for image recognition

IFSP (Sao Paulo Federal Institute of Technology)

Sao Paulo, Brazil

B.S. IN AUTOMATION AND CONTROL ENGINEERING

Jan. 2009 - Dez. 2013

- Development of an wireless lightweight device for fist angle measurement
- Development of an Arduino library for embedded Neural Nets

Skills_

Programming Python, MATLAB, .Net, LaTeX, Node

Engineering Automation, Control Design, Signal Processing, ABB 800xA, Siemens Step 7, Mining, Cement

DevOps Docker, Azure, TFS, DevOps, ABB Ability Edge

Back-end Flask, FastAPI, REST API

Languages Portuguese, English, Spanish, Italian

General Strong teamwork, International experience (15+ countries), speak in public

Work Experience _____

ABB Sao Paulo, Brazil

R&D ENGINEER

Oct. 2015 - Present

Feb. 2013 - Sep. 2015

- Developing products to reduce industrial costs and increase productivity for Mining, Aluminum and Cement industries.
- Supporting the development of Docker containers for ABB Ability and ABB Ability Edge
- Since 2019 Project leader of ABB Conveyor Roller Inspection Services (CRIS)
- - Coordinating teams worldwide
- - Defining technical specifications
- - Programming in low-level for robot motion and in high level for data analysis
- - International conference presentations
- - Listening to the customers to design new specifications and solutions
- - Business support for internal and external clients
- From 2015 to 2018 Tech leader and developer of ABB Ability AssetVista
- - Programming base libraries for development support
- - Converting maintenance experts know-how in code
- - Teaching teams around the world on how to develop AssetVista new algorithms
- - Supporting teams development
- · Comissioning and support the comissioning of projects globaly

ABB Sao Paulo, Brazil

PROJECT ENGINEER

• Developing and delivering solutions in Advanced Process Control

- Implementation of Model Predictive Control and Fuzzy Logics for optimization of cement plants
- Plant modeling and model evaluation using ABB APC (Advanced Process Control) and ABB 800xA
- Publication of case studies based on the optimization process achievements

March 18, 2020 Tiago Prata · Résumé 1